the puzzle analogy will work for people
and it lands but is it the best analogy
to use is it truthful is it honest is it
valid how are how can a speaker you know
validate some of the things that they're
saying so that people can trust in the
message in itself absolutely and this is
the piece of advice that you everyone
can do with their ideas that nobody does
and it Buggles me because it's so simple
when somebody starts a show like yours
when somebody starts a podcast or an
idea or a message that they have to
share with the world and they always
come up to me and say the following uh
Brandon uh you know 7 people are
watching me how do I get a 100 people to
watch me and I always ask him the
following question Ryan out of those
seven people who are watching you right
now Bob how many of those people have
you had a one-hour dinner conversation
with Bob will almost always answer zero
or one and that is crazy the best way to
validate your ideas is to talk to the
people who are actually listening to you
right so what I did and I think that's
why I've had some success in my career
is because when I when there were seven
people listening to master talk I met
all of them one onone for an hour when I
came up with puzzle that was when I was
coaching a client and she didn't
understand what I was saying on how to
structure a speech so I thought of
analogies in my head and I thought about
puzzle pieces and I was like whoa I
should probably make a YouTube video on
that and I wrote it down and it it
created it became content so all of the
knowledge that I share is always
prevalidated in the sense that I always
get the Insight from somebody who wants
to listen to me and the the reason why
you want to do that especially at the
beginning whether you're a business
owner who's selling a product or a
service or whether you're someone who
has a show like this one you always need
to pay attention to the
following why is it that this person
when they can be watching anything else
why are they watching me I mean when I
had 16 subscribers I thought was a loser
on YouTube I was like come on this is
stupid like I'm making YouTube videos in
my basement who would listen to this but
some people
did and you have to say out of 86,000
seconds stage was the final stage where
they
[Music]
actually to see any
success media came out of both of those
[Music]
things what's going on folks Ryan Perez
here with hustle Zone TV and uh you know
we've been doing this show for like you
know maybe four or five years I'm not
even counting I'm not counting um I'm
just happy to be here um with you guys
today and um hopefully I'm using the
right mic this time because last time I
was using the scratchy mic on my my um
on my what you call those things the
camera the the the Logitech camera so um
today uh we are going to be interviewing
somebody that is is pretty fun like
actually talking to him in the green
room and he's a really cool guy so uh
before we get there we got some house
cleaning to do um you know Monica black
diamond and I are bringing back the
hustle Zone jam session so but now we're
going to be pre- selecting the guests to
come up onto the show so if you guys are
interested to being part of the show
make sure to um to hit me up in the DMS
and what is hustle Zone TV we are uh the
world's first living documentary um our
living documentary will be launched um
January 1st
2021 so um or 2000 yeah 20 th did I say
2021 holy moly January 1 2021 yes so um
and it'll be a subscription base uh
we're going to be uh like our first set
of um shows will be interviews um you
know talking to people about culture
about life about entrepreneurship and so
much more more um and then you're you're
going to be able to find this episode
and every episode on all major uh
streaming platforms as well uh what else
do I have to say well I'm so happy we
we've reached over
40,000 uh followers on on Instagram or
not on Instagram sorry on Instagram and
YouTube collectively so uh we're super
excited about that so thank you guys all
for uh your continued support and if you
guys can do me a favor make sure to
share this out uh so that we can get as
many people on this uh broadcast uh
today so let's uh talk a little bit
about our guest let me just pull up his
bio uh so Brandon is founder of Master
talk a YouTube channel uh he started to
help the world master the world the art
of public speaking and communication he
coaches Purpose Driven entrepreneurs on
how to master their message and share
ideas with the world so folks I'm super
excited to have him on the show today
and like I got to tell you a little
secret he's a fellow kanuck yes you know
there's another one of us out there
right so um let's give it up
for Brendan kumara how's it going
brother very good Ryan how about
yourself man I'm doing good I'm doing
good so I um you know I welcome to go
live and prosper and you know we kind of
met in a really convenient way I'm not
going to tell everybody how we met
because then everybody's going to be on
it and I don't want everybody on it
so I'm joking but we we we met through
matchmaker. FM and and um you know when
I read your um when I read your your
your website and and and just did a
little bit of research and saw some of
your talks like you know you're a pretty
interesting guy uh so I'm so happy to
have you um on today's show uh what but
coming into the hustle Zone we usually
have a tradition and the tradition is
the first question I ask you is what is
your story so if you can start from the
very beginning how did you where did you
start and how did you come here of
course man thanks on so the story is
simple when I was 5 years old I grew up
in a city called Montreal in Canada so
like you said I'm a fellow kanak and
growing up in that City now most people
don't know this but French is one of the
few languages that you need to know so
this many languages he got a masters
when I was a kid my parents looked at me
and they said well Brendan you got to
learn how to speak French buddy so they
put me in a French education system
obviously I'm very fortunate they did
that when it came to presentations it
was a struggle imagine presenting in
general is already scary but now I had
to present in a language I didn't even
know so when I was in grade one or grade
two I'd look at the class and just go uh
bour and that was my my life when it
came to presentations anyways fast
forward a couple of years I went to
University right and in University in
business school I used to do these
things called case competitions so think
of it like professional sports but for
nerds so other guys my age were playing
football or basketball or baseball or
some other random sport that I didn't
really understand I used that same
competitive spirit and I applied it to
presentations for three years I
presented hundreds of times coached a
bunch of people on communication and
then when I started working in the
corporate world I just asked myself the
simple question which is how do I make a
difference in the world how do I
contribute more to society and that's
when I had the idea for master talk
because I realized that a lot of the
communication information out there is
really bad on YouTube so I started
making videos my mother's basement one
thing led to another and here we are
today awesome awesome and uh hold on one
second let me just zoom out here so uh
so you you saw that all the videos that
are on YouTube they were not as as great
for in terms of content but what about
the content did you find that was not so
great yeah so a couple of things the
first one is just the energy of the
presenters and the creators you know we
talk about public speaking it's usually
seen as a chore oh yeah I'm in school I
got to do this presentation and I'm at
work I got to do this thing and the
people on YouTube in communication were
also mirroring that same energy so
whenever they were talking about how to
add more energy in a presentation well
their videos would sound something like
this hey guys so today we're going to
learn how to add more energy into the
presentation I be like wait what they
they got no energy to begin with why are
they coaching other people on energy and
that was true with many of the other
subjects like how do you vary vocal
tones to display different emotions well
the video would sound something like
this hey hey guys uh so today we're
going to learn how to manage vocal toes
I was like wait wait a second these
people don't know what they talking
about so there's a couple of holes that
I saw in people's game when it came to
communication and public speaking and I
understood why the co content wasn't
really good and the reason is because a
lot of the people who make money as a
speech coach do really well for
themselves all you need is 10 15 clients
who pay you a pretty big package and
then you're done you that's pretty much
your business so most people who are
really good at communication and
coaching it generally don't make free
content at all especially not on YouTube
consistently so that's where I saw the
hole in the market and a need that
wasn't being met because a lot of people
who can't afford a speech coach still
want to communicate their ideas whether
they're the CEO of a nonprofit or even a
seven-year-old girl in Cambodia who just
wants to raise a bit of money for
charity I want to be that bridge for all
of those people and that was the uh that
was the the match to to master talk so I
I I've heard this before I mean you know
there are many um there are many
experts that uh
that come out and say hey I can help you
speak I can help you engage audiences I
can help you boost your brand and and
and whatnot um and you're and you're
right a lot of the the content that you
see is Cookie Cutter and and and whatnot
but what makes what makes you so special
like what is the specific thing um that
you add not you know and I know that
you've just mentioned that um uh you
know that you were able to fill in the
Gap in terms of being able to offer you
know offer some tools um on your YouTube
channel without being paid but what are
some of the strategies or tactics that
you that you think are you know unique
to you that can help people with their
speaking absolutely so here's the
general issue with the industry and then
we'll get into some of those tips and
techniques that I have to share for
everyone but the general issue Ryan is
that most of the information that shared
is highly academic and vague so let's
say you ask a speech coach so how do I
get better with the speech they would
say something like be
yourself get up on stage share your
message with the world which is great
but where's the practicality behind that
kind of just like okay well you're
telling me to just keep doing it which
isn't very helpful though it is true but
it's not super useful here's an example
of a good tip that I that I share on the
channel public speaking in many ways is
like a jigsaw puzzle you know those
thousand piece puzzles you kind of put
together with your family
yeah right so if I asked you Ryan and
you were doing this puzzle with your
family which pieces would you start with
first and
why uh I don't know you don't know wait
like a puzzle you know those jigsaw
puzzles like which pieces do you start
with
Earth I don't remember last time I I was
playing with a puzzle I usually don't
get that as an answer but for those who
are listening who probably know the
answer it's the corner
pieces right you know you do the corners
it's just easier to spot those pieces is
because they got edges on them right but
it's okay no worries so just just to
answer like for me when it comes to
puzzles I group I'm the way my brain
works is that I group Colors by colors I
sort them and then I start I don't look
at the the actual piece themselves I
group by by color I'm a designer so
and and also dyslexic so the way that I
see the world is is completely different
so I'll group the colors together and
then then I'll piece it all together
fair enough right so so you're
definitely in the super Geniuses of the
minority where you just kind of look at
the puzzle and you piece it together but
for most of us right going going through
the corners is probably the easiest bet
why because they're easy to spot and
easy to put together and then when you
have the framework you tackle the middle
the question we need to ask ourselves
Ryan is why don't we do that in public
speaking we have a presentation in two
days at work or at school so what do we
do we shove a bunch of content and other
words we start with the middle pieces
first and then when we get to the last
slide of that presentation it sounds
something like this uh yeah so
thanks that's probably 97% of all the
presentations I've seen in my
life so by applying puzzle this is what
it means much like a jigsaw puzzle start
your presentations by practicing the
corner pieces do the introduction 50
times not three times not five times 50
times think about the way you just inted
the show four years ago when you started
well maybe the intro wasn't as good it
was like like hey guys I'm Ryan and now
it's just like awesome hustle Zone
you're like you got the fire you got the
energy same thing with the conclusion
what's a great movie with the terrible
ending a terrible movie so present the
conclusion 50 times it won't take you
that long it's an hour each right
because an intro is a minute and a
conclusion is also a minute in two hours
of practice Ryan you'll have 10x your
communication skills because you look at
the introduction that you never did 50
times in a row kind of just go wow I'm
actually pretty good at this
communication thing and then you tackle
the middle but much like a jigsaw puzzle
who does puzzles alone do with the group
of friends do with people who want to
master communication even today as a
professional speaker Ryan I still
practice my Keynotes with my friends I
still practice my presentations with
them so that's the key start with the
edges tackle the middle that framework
you can use for the rest of your life
and and and what what are the outcomes
that that you would receive um from from
practicing cuz you know um not to be
Devil's Advocate but when I like for me
like because of my dyslexia I don't
necessarily practice I have you know key
points um that I know that I'm going to
talk about and I talk about and you know
I'm okay with uh you know freestyling it
but you know there's you have two you
have two points here you have
freestyling or canned messages and you
know when you're practicing practicing
practicing practicing um so much how do
you reach certain people because they
know it's a canned message it's like hi
my name is Ryan Perez with hustle Zone
TV and you know and it goes on and on
and this is what I'm going to do I got
five steps to help you uh you know trim
your Hedges and whatever but I I think
think that you know there has to be room
for people to um to be able to connect
with the audience and and you know I I
think with even with music and with rap
um you know or songwriting you know you
you kind of get into the Motions of
saying something repetitively over time
and then people understand but there's
always that there's always that one
person that wants to be able to connect
with you deeper and sometimes when
things are practiced too much it's hard
for people to receive the message so
what would be your perspective on that
right so that's a fair criticism that
you offer but I don't think it's in the
right angle and thanks Erin for great
stuff I just saw that comment quickly
but the point of driving is let me let's
use some examples you don't even take my
advice let's look at the the proof and
the pudding Tony Robbins has been doing
the same damn seminar for 40
years remember that that number 40 years
he's been doing the same set weinar
longer than I've been
alive and probably you too that's the
point I'm driving what the best speakers
in the world do is even if it is a quote
unquote canned message it's not I don't
I don't like the word canned it's not
really canned it's just they've
presented the same idea so many times
that it's just easier for them to
communicate it in an authentic thought
provoking way think about the way I'm
communicating to you right now Ryan sure
am I canning my message and writing down
everything I'm saying no but the reason
I can perform today is because this is
my 250th interview right right so it's
just sounds better even if I'm pretty
much answering the same questions that I
get all the time but why despite the
fact that my answers today are pretty
much the same ones I give in every other
show why are they Landing well at least
I hope anyways the reason is because
even if the idea is the same to me the
idea is new to you I I guarantee Ryan
there's somebody in this audience who's
who who just heard puzzle for the first
time and they just said whoa I never
thought of that before it's true
communication is exactly like a jigsaw
puzzle so even if for us or for me
rather that idea isn't new it's rather
the very old idea these days it's new to
those people so what I recommend is
different advice for different types of
speakers when you're getting started I
highly recommend mastering one
presentation because all of the best
speakers in the world do that and you
did that to a certain extent with this
format that you have for hustle Zone
you're not changing the format every
show and then as you get better what
happens is that you start to develop a
unique identity for who you want to be
as a speaker and that's when you start
getting creative but start with the
basics first and climb your way up to
the top awesome now what about
validating the idea uh because I feel
like you know people have these
messages you know they've practiced
they've gone through it and I mean I
agree with you you know um you there's
something I tell my son all the time
three piece and three hours if you want
to be good at anything it's practice
practice practice repetition repetition
repetition because you get into you know
it it builds confidence because then
you're not really it's not in your
Consciousness it's it's internal so by
me asking you that question wasn't me
saying that it's it's it's wrong to
practice you know the key parts of your
message but let's go a deep let's go um
a bit further and let's talk about
validating these ideas because you know
a lot of people do a bit of Google
search but they're not really getting to
the first principles of the conversation
and therefore um that can cause um some
problems because yeah maybe your puzzle
the puzzle analogy will work for people
and it lands but is it the best analy to
use is it truthful is it honest is it
valid how are how can a speaker you know
validate some of the things that they're
saying so that people can trust in the
message in itself absolutely and this is
the piece of advice that you everyone
can do with their ideas that nobody does
and it bugles me because it's so simple
when somebody starts a show like yours
when somebody starts a podcast or an
idea or a message that they have to
share with the world and they always
come up to me and say the following uh
Brandon uh you know seven people are
watching me how do I get a 100 people to
watch me and I always ask him the
following question Ryan out of those
seven people who are watching you right
now Bob how many of those people have
you had a one-hour dinner conversation
with Bob will almost always answer zero
or one and that is crazy the best way to
validate your ideas is to talk to the
people who are actually listening to you
right so what I did and I think that's
why I've had some success in my career
is because when I when there were seven
people listening to master talk I met
all of them one on one for an hour when
I came up with puzzle that was when I
was coaching a client and she didn't
understand what I was saying on how to
structure a speech so I thought of
analogies in my head and I thought about
puzzle pieces and I was like whoa I
should probably make a YouTube video on
that and I wrote it down and it it
created it became content so all of the
knowledge that I share is always
prevalidated in the sense that I always
get the Insight from somebody who wants
to listen to me and the the reason why
you want to do that especially at the
beginning whether you're a business
owner who selling a product or service
or whether you're someone who has a show
like this one you always need to pay
attention to the following why is it
that this person when they can be
watching anything else why are they
watching me I mean when I had 16
subscribers I thought I was a loser on
YouTube I was like come on this is
stupid like I'm making YouTube videos in
my basement who would listen to this but
some people did mhm a lot more people
than I thought did so I asked them I
said why are you listening to it and
they would say things like yeah I know
your quality of the video isn't that
great Brandon
but you're sharing stuff that nobody
really shares you're simplifying this
stuff so easily for people who are six
years old who are 14 years old and it's
from those insights that I was able to
dive so for your idea whether it's a
cupcake recipe or a show ask the people
who are already bought into the ideas
why they're bought in and use those
insights to validate and make your ideas
better now let's talk about outcomes
um I know we're at the 12:30 Mark here
um let's talk about outcomes because now
I've followed your advice I want
followers I want to increase my my
reach uh and um you know a lot of people
talk about you know like for me I could
say you know on my YouTube channel we
have 5,000 followers we have followers
on Instagram and and um and different
platforms um the way that I grew my
channel was just giving people what they
wanted um however
you know what works for me doesn't
necessarily work for everybody else so
when you're coaching people about public
speaking they're not necessarily
interested in the fact that they want to
learn how to public speak I I believe
that they are more interested in you
know increasing their
income um getting more followers getting
more reach um some of them want to be
like a Tony Robbins you know someone
them want to talk about mindful
Consciousness and they want to be a guru
um so in your perspective how does one
become viral how does one's message
because again we are talking about I
think that we can like when it comes to
business everyone has a different
message but they're they're still
talking about the same
subject you know so how do you get
beyond the crowd and how does your
message how can you amplify your message
so that um you can reach um more
audiences absolutely and here's my my
personal take on this the summary is
whenever you say someone whenever you
see someone's success never say wow
always ask how so let me repeat that
again whenever you see someone
successful never say wow wow this
person's so amazing focus on the how how
did they get there so you know people
look at people like Gary vaynerchuk he
has millions of followers but what they
don't see is that even if he has a
flight in two hours after a keynote he
spends 17 minutes talking to average
people oneon-one and still books anyways
why does he do that why does that make
any sense and that lesson that I'm
driving there has so many so so there's
so much more to that than just him
signing books it's this idea that the
way that you grow an audience is a lot
simpler than you think but it's not easy
if you want your first thousand on
YouTube you need to ask yourself who are
the first thousand who want to hear you
who want to hear from what do they
believe in what do they care about who
are they and then from that Insight then
you focus on that Niche and then you go
to the next one for me the answer was
very obvious at the beginning it was
podcast hosts podcast hosts are the
people who want Master talk to exist the
most for two reasons one because they
want to become better communicators
themselves and two they want to share
this knowledge on their own platform for
their own audiences so for me even if I
make the videos for everyone I Target
podcast so specifically and that's how
I've been able to grow so for you and
your ideas what you need to do is figure
out what Seth Goden calls the smallest
viable audience who are the first
thousand that would Rave for you because
a business is built on super fans a
following is built on super fans
everything that's meaningful in society
is built on super fans focus on those
thousand people and if you really want
to make it be sure you put as much
one-on-one time as possible I send voice
notes to everybody who DMS me on
Instagram even today even with the
success I have and Gary still does that
to a certain extent too these days not
everybody since he's getting he has a
lot of people messaging him now but
that's the key it's oneon-one jabbing
the secret to 10,000 followers is 10,000
conversations
period now I noticed something on your
YouTube
channel uh was doing a little bit um of
research and uh the one thing is that
today I I when I at your YouTube channel
you were you know you're dressed up your
background is um you know you have a
fireplace in the background you got the
best camera in the industry uh that's
definitely that's not true but
sure well the camera's good I think the
the lighting and whatnot and you know
and I think that it's very important for
presentation um and I know that you and
I we are in our covid most people are in
their covid uh most people when they're
doing these live streams they don't get
their haircut they don't do this because
they can't go because they're locked
down um so you know do you think that in
um with live streaming with uh public
speaking that presentation the way you
look um has an
impact this is an interesting question
it really depends who you're speaking to
so if you think about my YouTube channel
I mostly just did it in the suit shop
because I just felt like it just because
nobody else do that on YouTube so it's
just a way for me to be unique there's
no strategy behind that but as you can
tell I mean I'm literally sitting on a
mattress as I'm speaking to you right
now right but I think the key that I
want to drive is it all depends on the
person you're trying to reach and the
person you want to become so if you all
have the aspiration of having a show
like Ryan well Ryan isn't wearing a suit
every day when he does shows so that
automatically tells us that we don't
need to either right but it also doesn't
necessarily mean that if I'm someone who
who puts suits on and does shows in the
YouTube that you necessarily need to do
that either I think the strategy a
general frameworking give people is why
do you want to do videos why do you want
to create content who are you creating
it for and what would they appreciate
the most from you based on your own
unique talents and aptitudes so in my
case because I was young I'm the
youngest speech coach on YouTube I
believe so because of that I wanted to
appeal to everybody not just the people
who are younger than me but the people
old old than me so they that so I can
have the wisdom for them to learn from
me as well that's why I decided to put a
suit on to just look older right so so
it's just a a way to to think about your
brand and I also like suits so it works
well with who I am yeah it's just about
aligning everything yeah yeah for sure
and folks uh I'm gon to share my screen
with you guys this is his Instagram
account um you know because I'm in
branding look at this guy he's so sharp
I appreciate it brother it's very kind
of this is this is a pretty good um you
know cuz I I like your approach your
approach is you know you're you're smart
you're sophisticated and you know you're
taking you're taking your um you're
taking your brand seriously and I think
that I think that is very important and
I think that um hold on how do I get out
of this screen now um I think that's
very important um to present yourself in
such a way because I I usually tell my
clients like I think the most important
thing that you ought to do if you're
trying to reach a large group of people
people um you have you got you have to
have you got to get your head shot you
have to have a head shot you have to
have um you know you have to have a look
in a way that people can identify with
you because once that that impression is
stuck on someone's mind that's how
they're always going to remember you so
when you you when you show up
differently they they like okay I I
don't I don't get it but it depends
right because for me I've always been
you know my my my business this which is
sponsoring this BR broadcast uh bow tie
creative um I usually wear a bow tie you
know and everywhere I go it's a bow tie
it looks great but I think presentation
is just as important as the message
because I think that the one of the the
biggest barriers to communication is
trust and that's going to be my next
question for you how does a person
beyond the puzzle pieces how do they
build trust with their
audience right so so for me trust stems
from one thing which is adding value but
let's add more layer to that what does
adding value even mean righty for me
adding value is the following definition
tell me something I don't already know
do you now I don't mean to interrupt but
do you say that at the beginning because
again I'm seeing you for the first time
you know I'm hearing you for the first
time or you're reaching out to me um or
I see you on YouTube you know what is
that how do you break that trust Factor
at the very beginning because normally
the value is within the conversation not
necessarily at the beginning of the
conversation so what are some elements
um that you can bring to your audience
because I think that Icebreaker is what
most people uh want to know when it
comes to you know public speaking and
Communications is how can I develop
trust almost immediately because at not
only are we speaking doing public
speaking but we're also co- calling
right meeting people for the first time
to to you know because when you're a
startup you got to call you got to knock
on doors you got to you have to book
some deals so that you can you know pay
your bills so what are other ways that a
person can do to build that trust right
so so I'll give you my perspective on
this because I'm obviously not a code
calling expert in the sense that I think
that the best way to develop trust is
through value and I think that is
possible to develop that trust and value
from the first second of a conversation
I'll give you the best example with me
you don't have to take my advice as to
whether I have good YouTube videos or
not you could look at me and go this
guy's on a mattress why should I listen
to this guy or you can go watch the the
first second of a YouTube video and in
15 seconds you'll be like oh okay this
guy actually knows how to speak so for
me value always come and trust is always
built on people who give a result who
have achieved the result you know don't
you find it crazy in society Ryan that
you know doctors who are obese are
giving you health advice how does that
make any sense
you know what oops I you out screen
there uh you know what I think that
there are people that are obes that are
giving advice and I mean you know but
they it doesn't
mean it doesn't mean that they're not
right what they're telling you right but
at the same time going back to what you
said right just because right doesn't
necessarily mean that're they're wrong
but would you prefer listening over that
guy or that girl over the the guy who's
actually fit right
I'm actually in shape this analogy
applies for everything for example why
would you listen to a relationship
expert who is telling you how to get
into a relationship but isn't in a
relationship themselves or has it
thriving like it's just it just makes no
sense in my opinion so me for me it's
all about being congruent right how do
you create alignment with who you are
the work that you're doing and
delivering on that work as quickly as
possible that's why my my advice to
people especially for people who are
young and getting started is show don't
tell don't tell people you're a speech
coach don't tell people you got a show
show them here's my show what do you
think about it here's my public speaking
YouTube video sure I'm young watch this
video tell me if I'm knowledgeable or
not that's the key you want to show
people as much as you can and not any
not like back to your cold calling not
everyone wants to hear from you not
everybody is going to but the one person
who does pick up the phone who's going
to take seven minutes and say let's see
what this guy has to offer or gal has to
offer that's is your to build trust and
for me you know my success you know I've
been able to I've been very blessed you
I get to guest on 15 20 shows a week how
was it how was I able to build those
relationships because I always deliver
on shows I come I overd deliver I add a
lot of value and then they go of course
I'll intro you that's the key build
trust with the people who actually want
to build it with you and honor it by
delivering value that they just can't
get anywhere else awesome I think that I
think that's I think that's amazing I
think um it's very important for us to
to to to build value and I think it's
also um important for us to do uh
competitive research because you you
know one way of showing value is that
people have to already be in that
alignment that there's already existing
information out there for them to
compare um you with all the other
YouTube videos or the other speakers
that are talking about the same things
but being able to look at your
competitors and being like you know what
a is saying this B is saying this I'm
going to say C you know which is a
little bit of a but you know it's um you
know it's something a little bit
different so that people can uh so I can
reach a bigger audience for you you're
value to me really you're a younger guy
that um you know that you have this this
presence of Education wealth and I think
like you said Joe um show your audience
it will help a young kid that wants to
become an entrepreneur or whomever or
even a public speaker it helps them say
hey you know what I have I have a I have
a a milestone I have a goal here I have
um someone that inspires me to to kind
of get to a certain level so I think um
I think a lot of the things that you're
saying um is pretty concrete so I I
thank you so much for that uh we have
some people in the chat um Robert says
hi Ryan hi Brendan hey Robert says Hi Ka
so Ka was saying pass the eyeball test
for the uh audience that you're speaking
to that's the comment that we were
talking about in terms of looks um uh
she says the youngest speech coach on
YouTube awesome title thanks
Ka um 10,000 conversions and then she
also says not just follower followers
that will that will send me clients or
become clients or uh turn into friends
one of the the final questions before we
um we have 15 minutes are you good for
15 more minutes yeah yeah we 15 so um
before we get into our lightning round
um we talk about like increasing
followers and making money Etc as the
outcome but at an end of a speech or a
talk what let's put business hats on
what are people supposed to do how do
they how do they convert those listeners
into
customers simple one-on-one
conversations how did I build a
successful practice in
speaking I went on a bunch of shows I
figured out who my ideal customer was
and eventually I figured out a product
or service that they wanted from me so
the first thing you need to ask ask
yourselves is the following question
what does the world need me most to do
right now and
why if you can ask answer that question
you'll figure out exactly what product
or service you're supposed to be
offering the world there's a bunch of
stuff I could have St I could have
started a YouTube channel called Master
life and gave life advice all day I
could have started a master career
YouTube channel and gave career coaching
advice and I would have been okay at it
when it came to public speaking that was
the one thing that I IND at the most
that I was just way better than every
other skill I had in my Arsenal and then
once I knew what that skill was the next
question I asked myself is who needs
that skill the most and who is willing
to pay for that skill and then after I I
landed on technology Executives and then
after you land on the niche the next
question is to interview them talk to
them have dinner conversations with them
understand their struggles create an
offer out of it and then sell the offer
back to them it's simple it always
always begins and ends with your
audience my friend always told me it's
probably the wisest advice I got when I
started becoming a content creator which
is the following and it's hard advice
not many people will follow it but it's
just the truth you are the slave to your
audience if you think you are better
than your audience if you think you are
above your audience you will never win
this game and I always love using Gary
as an example really anybody even Tony
Robbins is a great example these people
don't have to do seminars anymore they
make pretty good money why do do they
still do it why they still talk to the
general public because at the end of the
day the best content creators understand
that we are the slave to our audiences
for without our audience we are nothing
so talk to your audience over and over
again and figure out an offer and trust
me if you actually did the work they
will be excited and enthusiastic to buy
from you so how do you know like in
that's in a public space because you
know you'll have zoom conversations and
live streams in this nature how do you
know cuz some people are just watching
because they you know but they may not
be in your market so how do you qualify
them to ensure that you're dealing with
the right people right so so the way
that I think about it is eventually you
know as your audience grows you're right
like honestly I actually make the videos
for people who can't afford me so it's a
very different Market I have a different
strategy there but you're right for the
people who do end up becoming paid
clients of mine there's a certain
portfolio of person there's a there's a
profile of who that person is so for
example for me it's a technology
executive who makes between $100,000 and
$250,000 a year who is a manager who
wants to become a senior executive
someday that's my that's my ideal client
Persona so people who don't match those
criteria I don't pursue them but in an
audience of let's say now let's say
hustle zone is with 40,000 how many of
those executives are there maybe seven
maybe 14 it's probably more than 14 if
I'm being honest and that's and if you
got 40 of them to sign up for your
program you charge them each $5,000
that's a pretty good business you got
there and then all those executive Ives
know all the other exe if you're
actually as good as you say you are they
know a bunch of the other Executives
that's what happened to me so I go on
shows for free like I just add a bunch
of value and then at show 51 you know
one of them just went hey Brendon I like
what you're doing do you do coaching and
then I coach them blow their minds and
then after it's just referrals and now I
just do shows for fun so so awesome
awesome now I'm gonna ask you a trick
question before we get to it there's one
more um a trick question because I think
that when you are presenting you are on
the up and up you are positive you are
projecting a
message um because you have something to
sell now what if your reputation got
tarnished in in in any particular um
situation your reputation's um tarnished
but you still need to speak you still
need to put yourself out there how does
one um use their skills to change their
their current narrative because folks
narratives are bought you know or are
created whether you create them or not
you know so how do you change
perspectives and change narratives um
you know with your public speaking
skills interesting I I've never gotten
the reputation tarnish question before I
don't think that'll happen to most of us
as long as you build it right but what I
will say okay the main reason you want
to personal brand everyone is so you
speak your own truth if you don't create
your own content other people will
create it for you what do I mean by that
if I don't make the effort to create my
own stuff to say what I think to show
what I believe on shows other people
will make that decision for me they'll
say Brendan is this Brendan is that
Brendan doesn't know what he's talking
about Brendan is this but if you and
this applies to all of us by having a
personal brand in our business by
communicating our thoughts and ideas to
the world we are showing people what we
believe so even if your reputation is
tarnished cuz you are going to make
mistakes along the way the goal is to
keep communicating you might not do it
on a big stage for a while but you're
going to have to keep doing it through
social media to figure out who still
wants to buy into and then work again
and start from Ground Zero again but
ideally the remedy is I don't I'm pretty
sure none of you have tarnished your
reputation yet is to be thoughtful about
it since day one who do you want to be
what do you want to stand for what
values do you want to have and as long
as you're aligned with those values
you'll always when and I and I'll give
mine to make this more concrete the way
that I summarize my personal brand is
the following I want to be a classy man
of the people what does this mean this
means I'm someone who's who will always
talk to somebody on the street who comes
up to me and says oh you know like I
love master tole that stuff I I'll
always make time for that kind of stuff
but I'll do it with class so even if I
still have my my cool flashy suits in my
YouTube channels I always make sure to
appear very casual in podcast
appearances so people still see see me
as just a member of the community so I'm
a member of the community with class
that's the personal brand I went with so
for you you need to clearly Define what
that is for you and you'll have a lot
more success and there's no way you'll
tarnish your brand as long as you still
like sure but you know I've I've dealt
with customers that have tarnished their
brands I think that's you know you know
people that you know it it's true it's
it's not uh I think that you're not
always going to your your message may be
the same but you're you're always going
to encounter changes in the market Place
changes in behaviors and attitudes and
you have to also be able to adjust and
be able to Pivot um your message and you
also have to show growth because how you
start is not always how you're going to
end right you know it it's just it
doesn't necessarily mean that you
charish your that's why I asked the
question because um you know the the
power of speaking is when you learn how
to speak you can change opinions you can
change the way that people see you you
can change the way that people see a
subject so I think it's very important
for people um to to be able to Pivot to
be able to research to do more research
or to find new audiences um you know to
to illustrate their their their messages
or to articulate their messages too um
because you're not always going to win
people 100% of the time it just doesn't
work you know every business has an
incline and it has a decline so you have
have to know how to how to how to what
strategies to use when um you know
especially when you are you're in the
public eye uh we have one more qu or not
a question but we have a comment and
Robert says indeed communication matters
greatly including with myself and he
says it um it is being of service to
others um um that the path of Joy opened
up to me so perfect so we are at the
lightning
round I don't got any
sound effects but I was hoping you out
there thank you talking or
texting definitely
talking favorite day of the
week oh
Saturday favorite City uh in US besides
the or sorry favorite city in Canada
besides the one you live in oh crap I
was definitely going to pick Montreal oh
jeez every other City sucks in Canada
besides Montreal I said it live here I'm
kidding Halifax is great I really
enjoyed Halifax Halifax uh name your
parents uh name nickname your parents
used to call
you nickname my parents oh uh my mom
calls me cunden which is Tamil for mini
good I don't know why she does that Al
it's kind of weird but I don't know if
she calls me that it's weird well that's
it's good it's aspiring thing to live up
to last last song you've downloaded ever
probably something
Korean uh would you you rather be able
to speak every language in the world or
be able to talk to
animals every language around the world
awesome and uh questions these are just
lightning round questions you're like
what do you like better burgers or
fries just just helps people relate to
you um favorite favorite holiday oh I
don't really take holidays but if I had
to pick one it would probably be uh uh
I'm so bad at this oh man you caught me
good uh it's probably something in the
summer maybe like a cada a day yeah cada
a day
wo um how long does it take for you to
get
ready three minutes I literally get up
in the morning I have my first meeting 1
minutes later so I don't uh yeah I don't
I spend like very little time getting
ready awesome and uh scale from 1 to 10
how good of a driver are you negative3
that's why I don't drive I have my
license stuff but uh for the good
Society have chosen not to use the
vehicle that I've been nice nice fill in
fill in the blank Taylor Swift is
amazing I'm a huge fan actually awesome
and invisibility or super
strength o
invisibility
invisibility and at what age do you want
to
retire as early as possible so I can
spend more time on Master talks I'm I'm
shooting for 28 now okay what type of
music do you listen to everything Korean
music Justin Bieber uh rock music like I
listen I karaoke in eight different
languages Ryan so I'm pretty messed up I
listen to pretty much everything except
for like
metal awesome awesome and then uh
Michael Jackson or
Prince oh hard to make a decision
because I'm not really uh well
researched on either but probably MJ
right to pick probably MJ if you had to
pick and then the last question which I
asked all of my my guests um is it wrong
for a vegetarian or vegan um to eat
animal
crackers no as long as they're happy I'm
happy that's what matters long as it
doesn't have any milk products you
should be
fine so uh so Brandon uh tell us where
we can find you absolutely so for those
you want want to check out the YouTube
videos it's Master talk in one word and
if you want to send me a message you can
find my handle over there as well okay
awesome and um what um is there any
prerequisites that they should have um
you know how what is the best person for
you um in terms of a client uh I don't
come on shows to promote the business so
feel free to just message me if you have
a question to comment I'm happy to
engage answer any questions and I would
love your feedback on the videos perfect
well you guys heard it here folks uh I I
actually really like this conversation
and thank you so much Brendan for for
for coming on um if you guys haven't
done so already please follow him on
Facebook you can follow him on Instagram
you can follow him on YouTube I've
checked out his stuff his stuff is
actually really good uh so thank you so
much Brendon for for hopping into the
hustle Zone we have one more tradition
on the hustle Zone um so this one is um
going to be very interesting so uh what
we're going to be doing is a call and
response so when I say welcome to the I
need you to scream hustle Zone as loud
as you can oh geez my mom's not gonna
like this one I'll try I'll do something
measured okay so I'll say welcome to the
and then we say hustle zone so one two
three welcome to the
[Music]
H one more time you got to give me one
more time give me a little
bit welcome to the hustle
hustle you're nuts man I love it thanks
for but thank you thank you so much
Brendan for coming in and folks if you
guys haven't done so already make sure
you guys follow him on social media um
and then follow us on social media all
the links are in the description uh and
uh we are still doing our GoFundMe um uh
we're still running our GoFundMe
campaign for the world's first living
documentary we're going to be talking to
cultures all over the world about their
cultural
experiences um you know to show the
world that the world uh that cultures
are not a monolith just because I'm
black for example doesn't mean that I
share the same values as someone that
lives in Jamaica Etc so we definitely
want um you guys' support uh and you
know we're going to be launching January
1 two uh
2021 so here's the trailer and I'll talk
to you guys later
peace hi my name is Ryan Perez I'm owner
and founder of hustle Zone
TV we are putting together a
documentary that will be the first of
its kind to be a NeverEnding documentary
accounting for the lives the lifestyles
cultures and traditions of black and
Latino communities around the
world we want to let the world
know our communities are not a
monolith we're unique we're
diverse and with all of our
diversity we inform mainstream culture
this is the world's first living
documentary yes thank you guys so much
for tuning in I hope you guys enjoyed
this uh Brendan was actually pretty fun
uh and uh think he has a lot of things
to offer uh and you know when you get
into the hustle Zone you know you know
we don't play we are about that life we
want to make sure that um you know you
guys as our audience we want to make
sure that you guys are getting good
questions um and good interactions um
with each and every one of our guests
because we want them to give we don't
want just caned messages but we want
them to we want our guests to give more
and you know just like this broadcast it
was it really cool to to have that young
man on the show so thank you guys so
much for for tuning in to hustle Zone TV
Monica and I will be back we'll be back
uh with the hustle Zone jam session uh
we don't announce